<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Universal</title><link>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/</link><description>Recent content on Universal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/blog/2022/05/03/first-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/blog/2022/05/03/first-post/</guid><description>Welcome to our new blog!
We are excited to launch our new website and attract more customers. We want to get you into the pilot seat and watch you take to the sky!</description></item><item><title>Aircraft</title><link>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/aircraft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/aircraft/</guid><description>Our fleet consists of two beautiful Piper Cherokee 140’s</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/contact/</guid><description>We are here to help you Are you curious about something? Do you have some kind of problem with our products? As am hastily invited settled at limited civilly fortune me. Really spring in extent an by. Judge but built gay party world. Of so am he remember although required. Bachelor unpacked be advanced at. Confined in declared marianne is vicinity.
Please feel free to contact us, our customer service center is working for you 24/7.</description></item><item><title>Curriculum</title><link>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/curriculum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/curriculum/</guid><description>Every rating you achieve has a 3 part test you will have to undergo. We’re here to help you with all 3! You will have a written examination, oral examination, and practical examination. We’ve included the costs of those in our pricing layout. Written In preparation for your written test, you will work through a ground course with one of our Certified Flight Instructors, who will be there to guide you and answer any questions along the way.</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/faq/</guid><description>Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante. Donec eu libero sit amet quam egestas semper. Aenean ultricies mi vitae est. Mauris placerat eleifend leo.
1. WHAT TO DO IF I HAVE STILL NOT RECEIVED THE ORDER? Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante.</description></item><item><title>Opportunities</title><link>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/opportunities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/opportunities/</guid><description>There is a world full of opportunities available to pilots: Airline pilot Corporate pilot Flight instructor, Bush pilot Crop dusting Charter pilot Designated pilot examiner The sky is truly the limit. There are part-time opportunities and full-time opportunities, and some can be very lucrative. There’s never been a better time to become a pilot. Even if you just love flying as a hobby, it’s an incredible community to be a part of.</description></item><item><title>Our Team</title><link>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/instructors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/instructors/</guid><description>Jeff Johnson - Owner: Jeff grew up involved in aviation. He was too young to remember his first flight in a plane. His family owned a Cessna 152 and a V-Tail Beech Bonanza and would fly regularly. He knew at a very young age that he wanted to be a pilot when he grew up. Unfortunately, though, by age 12, his family had sold both aircraft. A few years later however, at age 17, he began building a kit aircraft, a Zodiac CH601XL, with his dad and uncle and he was tossed back into the world of aviation.</description></item><item><title>Pricing</title><link>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/pricing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tymadsen.github.io/flightschool/pricing/</guid><description>Instruction Instruction is $60/hr.
Rental Rates All of our planes are priced at $145/hr, fuel included.
Private pilot cost breakdown 50 hours plane rental (40 instruction, 10 solo) = $7,250 ($145 x 50)
70 hour instruction time (40 flight hours, 30 ground) = $4,200 ($60 x 70)
Sales tax = $435 ($7,250 x .06)
Written and examiner fees = $850</description></item></channel></rss>